<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Welcome to My Blog on misfitMojo</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Welcome to My Blog on misfitMojo</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanderings of a restless mind – in search of meaning, refusing to conform, a misfit channeling the spirit of solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Library</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/library/library/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/library/library/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These books represent the rabbit holes I’ve gone down over the years and the ideas and topics I’ve been curious about and engaged with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2021&#34;&gt;2021
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Klara And The Sun – Kazuo Ishiguro
Em and the Big Hoom – Jerry Pinto
Man without A Country – Kurt Vonnegut
She has her Mother’s laugh – Carl Zimmer
Dune Messiah – Frank Herbert
Dune – Frank Herbert
A Million Mutinies Now – VS Naipaul
Robots and Empire – Asimov
Robots of Dawn – Asimov
The Naked Sun – Asimov
Wanderers, Kings and Merchants – Peggy Mohan
The Power of Myth – Joseph Campbell
In spite of the Gods – Edward Luce
Power Systems – Noam Chomsky
Stoner – John Williams
One Hundred years of Solitude – Gabriel Garcia Marquez
On the Origin of Tepees- Jonnie Hughes
Why Orwell Matters – Christopher Hitchens
Men without Women – Murakami
Kannur – Ulekh NP
The Rum Diary – Hunter S Thompson
The Little Prince
A Visit from the Goon Squad – Jennifer Egan
Free Will – Sam Harris
The Gods Themselves – Isaac Asimov
India Moving – Chinmay Tumbe
Stumbling on Happiness – Daniel Gilbert
My Story – Kamala Das
The restaurant at the end of the universe – Douglas Adams
The Hitchhiker’s guide to the galaxy – Douglas Adams
Sirens of Titan – Kurt Vonnegut
Delhi: City of Djinns – William Dalrymple
The Illicit Happiness of Other People – Manu Joseph
Mr Majestic – Zac O Yeah
Finding Fish – Sanath Subramaniam
Nudge – Thaler &amp;amp; Sunstein
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2020&#34;&gt;2020
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;An Ordinary Person’s guide to Empire – Arundhati Roy
The Stranger – Albert Camus
Hooked – Nir Eyal
Our films their films – Satyajit Ray
Life of Pi – Yann Martel
Siddhartha – Herman Hesse
The Everything Store – Brad Stone
Genghis Khan and the Making of the Modern World – Jack Weatherford
Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck – Mark Manson
Purple Hibiscus – Chimamanda Adiche
Winners Take All- Anand Giridhardas
Politics, Women, Well being: The Kerala Model – Robin Jeffrey
India: A Wounded Civilization – V S Naipaul
Malevolent Republic – KS Komireddi
The Namesake – Jhumpa Lahiri
The Underground Railroad – Colin Whitehead
Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas – Hunter S Thompson
Being Indian – Pavan K Varma
The Doctor and the Saint – Arundhati Roy
Annhilation of Caste – BR Ambedkar
The Caves of Steel – Asimov
Kitchen Confidential: Antony Bourdain
The Man in the High Castle – Philip K Dick
The Idea of India – Sunil Khilnani
Man’s Search for Meaning – Viktor Fankl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;My Father Baliah – Y.B. Satyanarayana
Homo Deus – Yuval Noah Harari
Nobody Can Love You More – Mayank Austen Soofi
At the Existentialist Cafe – Sarah Bakewell
Midnight’s Children – Salman Rushdie
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;A Storm of Swords – George R. R. Martin
Talking Pictures: How to Watch Movies – Ann Hornaday
Tipping Point – Malcolm Gladwell
India After Gandhi -Ramachandra Guha
A God in Ruins – Kate Atkinson
The Old Man and the Sea –  Ernest Hemingway
The Autobiography of Malcolm X – Alex Haley and Malcolm X
The Golden Compass – Philip Pullman
Shantaram – Gregory David Roberts
Burmese Days – George Orwell
The Subtle Knife – Philip Pullman
The Amber Spyglass – Philip Pullman
The Beatle Years – Tony Barrow
Across the Universe: The Beatles in India – Ajoy Bose
One Hundred Years of Solitude – Gabriel García Márquez
Maus – Art Spiegelman
The Bachelor of Arts – R. K. Narayan
Exit West – Mohsin Hamid
The Silk Roads – Peter Frankopahn
Keep the Aspidistra Flying – George Orwell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;It Can’t Happen Here – Sinclair Lewis
Slaughterhouse-Five – Kurt Vonnegut
The Circle – Dave Eggers
Harry Potter Series – J K Rowling
The Cursed Child – J K Rowling
Nine Lives – William Dalrymple
Ready Player One – Ernest Cline
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;A Bend in the River – V.S. Naipaul
Miguel Street – V.S. Naipaul
The Five People You Meet in Heaven – Mitch Albom
The Lord of the Rings – J. R. R. Tolkien
The End of Eternity – Isaac Asimov
2001: A Space Odyssey – Arthur C. Clarke
One Hundred Years of Solitude – Gabriel García Márquez
Love in the Time of Cholera – Gabriel García Márquez 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Book Review : Chronicle of a Death Foretold</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronicle-of-a-death-foretold/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronicle-of-a-death-foretold/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a fairly short book that I read through in one sitting on a lazy holiday morning. The gripping storytelling and the layered non-linear plot that flitted across time and characters kept me hooked. The author Gabriel Garcia Marquez is known for pioneering a style of literature known as magic realism, blending fantasy and the ordinary. Also a popular journalist, he brings a journalistic touch to this complex tale of murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows the unnamed author trying to understand the events behind a murder that shook his village almost 27 years ago. The victim Santiago Nasar, was a childhood friend of the author. He was hacked to death on the doorsteps of his home. The murderers were known to everyone and to the victim himself. They’d been going around the village announcing that they were going to murder Santiago. This was mistaken for the drunken rambling of young men who had been revelling too long. A wedding party unlike any the village had seen had taken place over the weekend. A wedding which in fact acts as a catalyst for Santiago’s murder. The would-be murderers too do not want to commit the murder and were looking for someone to stop them. The whole village knew of the murder that was about to take place, and yet Santiago’s fate had been sealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are taken through recollections made by the characters who are still alive all those years later. They recite their memories of that fateful day, of how each had crossed paths with Santiago Nasar. He almost flows past them to his death. Many of them have lived and some have died, consumed by the regret that they could have prevented the senseless tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The senseless nature of events that lead to murder could be dismissed as being too convenient in any other novel. Gabriel Marquez’s beautiful writing paints a picture that is magical and poignant, yet so ordinary and mundane. These are people going about their lives, with their own petty grievances and feuds, weaving their own intricate inner stories. The series of chance events that come together and lead to the murder leaves us pondering the random nature of our own lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed this story is about so much more, mine has been a very reductive telling of the plot. One that does not even mention many of the major players in this drama. I would suggest you read the book to enjoy the themes, the personalities, their motivations and the tragedies that befall them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What interested me the most, was what the story says about the contingent nature of our lives. Almost always on a razor’s edge, never certain where we might fall. While it’s an impossible task to map the true impact of what we do. Our actions, the small decisions we make every day, might not end up aiding a murder. And hopefully, unlike the people of this village, we won’t have to live decades with the maddening weight of our actions or inaction. With the weight of the knowledge that our actions could have saved the life of a man whose death was foretold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
